Guide to the Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Goldsen, Rose papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
- Series II. Writings and Publications
  - Radio Programs
    - Radio Program - Miscellaneous
      - Front sheets for program scripts - 1975 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Copyright - "Blowing the Whistle on Broadcasting" - 8/76 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Ithaca Journal - Radio program announcements - 4/20-7/27/74 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Ithaca Journal - RKG weekly columns - 7/27-10/26/74 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Ithaca Journal - "Leisure" Section - problem of access letters of support - Oct. 1974 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Quickie broadcasts (Box 4, Folder 65)
        [clippings, notes]
    - Radio Program Fan Mail (in reverse chronological order)
      - Fan Mail 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Fan Mail 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Fan Mail 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Fan Mail 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Fan Mail 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Fan Mail and Replies (Replies Dates 1/20-22/76) (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Fan Mail Nov-Dec, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Fan Mail July-Oct, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Fan Mail Jan-June, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Fan Mail July-Dec, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Fan Mail Jan-June, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Fan Mail 1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Lectures, Conferences, Hearings
    - 1977-84(in reverse chronological order)
      - Reconstructive Knowledge - Amherst Conference n.d. (c 1980s) (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Appearances (New York State) 10/84 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Association of Northamerican Colombianists conference 6/13-15/84 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        [Raymond Williams corresp 8-9/83]
      - Local Appearances 5/83 - 5/84 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Social Trends and Outlook" Conference, Ithaca 4/10/84 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        [text of speech on 1984; notes]
      - "Women & Labor Market Policy" Conference, ILR 10/5-7/84 (in honor of Alice Cook) (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Monadnock Summer Lyceum, New Hampshire 8/83 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        [RKG - Ral Cole/David Strien corresp 2-10/83]
      - "Health and Society" conference, University of Barcelona 4/25/83 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        [RKG, "Love Canal: The Myth of Science and Politics," corresp]
      - Workshop on Computers and Personal Values, Hobart and William Smith Colleges 4/20-21/83 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        [notes c 20pp]
      - Conference on Culture and Communication, Temple University, Philadelphia 3/24-26/83 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - "The Second Age of Television" conference, New School, NYC 2/83 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - "Building Democratic Communications" conference, Philadelphia, 11/12-14/82 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - "Toward a Sustainable and Just Society" - Eco-Justice Conference, Cornell 10/22-24/82 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
        "The Television Explosion" - Nova (PBS) 2/14/82, R 2/17 & 2/20/82 [transcript, reviews, letters, fan mail]
      - Ucla Colloguia - "Privacy and Democracy" 10/10-12/81 (Charles Firestone) (Box 5, Folder 15)
        [transcript of RKG talk, 14 pp]
      - Semiotics Conference, Cornell 10/22-3/81 (Box 5, Folder 16)
        [RKG notes c 50pp]
      - "Taking Charge" conference, Washington/ DC 9/25-26/81 - Ralph Nader and Public citizen - 10th Anniversary (Box 5, Folder 17)
        [Rachel Shimshak letters 9-10/81; notes 5pp]
      - "Taking Charge" Conference - continued (Box 5, Folder 18)
        [RKG notes c 40pp]
      - National commission on Working Women, Washington, DC, 9/21/81 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        [corresp w/ Sally Steenland, Elizabeth D. Koontz 2-9/81]
      - American Sociological Association annual meeting, Toronto, 8/24-28/81: panel - Tom Kennedy, etc. (Box 5, Folder 20)
        [notes, correspondence]
      - Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers union, Washington, DC (Carolyn Jacobson) Fall 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Local Appearances 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Edward R. Murrow Symposium, Washington state Universit 4/15-17/81 (Box 5, Folder 23)
        [Jerry L. Salvaggio corresp 7-11/80; RKG lecture text: "Metaphor and Language as Clues to the Meaning of New Information Technologies" 9/22/80. Invitation cancelled for financial reasons.]
      - Quinebaug Valley Community College 4/15/81 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        [Nancy Chan corresp 2-4/81, Terry Russ letter 4/22/81]
      - "Take Back the Night," Ithaca 4/10/81 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        [Susan He Herman letters 1981]
      - Women's Studies Colloquium, Cornell 3/24/81 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        [RKG notes 7pp]
      - "Women in the Economy," course for cooperative Ext ens i agents, Ithaca 3/23-27/81 (Box 5, Folder 27)
        [Paul Eberts letter 4/81]
      - "The Consumer and cable Television" conference, Washington, DC 2/27-28/81 (Box 5, Folder 28)
        [RKG letter to Sam Simon; RK notes 16pp]
      - "The Consumer and Cable Television" conference, expens - Washington 2/26-3/1/81 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - MacNeil-Lehrer Report, "Soap Operas," 12/25/80 (Box 5, Folder 30)
        [transcript including interview with RKG]
      - "Creative Approaches to Ending Sex Discrimination in Higher Education," ILR Extension, Ithaca 11/7-9/80 (Box 5, Folder 31)
        [Jennie Parley letter 11/80]
      - International Institute of Communications conference, Ottawa 9/8-11/80 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - International Institute of Communications conference 9/8-11/80 - position papers (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - IIC Conference papers II (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - "Future of Telecommunications" conference, Science Museum of Minnesota, St. Paul, 9/5-6/80 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        [corresp w/ Linda J. Camp, David Chittenden, Jim Hayden, Carol Pin 5-9/80]
      - "Party Line, West Virginia," public radio 9/3/80 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Local appearances 1979-80 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - World Communication Conference, Annenberg School, Philadelphia 5/12-14/80 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        [corresp w/ George Gerbner, Elvira Lankford 1-7/80]
      - World Communication Conference 5/12-14/80 - position papers I (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - World Communication Conference 5/12-14/80 - position papers II (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - World Communication Conference - position papers III (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - "Stereotypes and Mass Communications: A Marriage of Convenience" - talk at Suny Binghamton Women's Studies 4/14/80 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        [corresp w/ Joan Smith, Patricia Rehberg 9/79-5/80]
      - "Television in the Developing World" conference, Winnipeg 3/29/80 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        [corresp w/ Jack Steinbring, Nicholas Tavuchis 12/79-3/80; Caren Deming letter 6/80; RKG lecture text: "Cultural Invasion by Television and Its Support Systems"]
      - "Technology; Over the Invisible Line?" conference, San Francisco 3/19-22/80 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - "Technology: Over the Invisible Line?" conference, 3/1 22/80 - position papers I (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - "Technology: Over the Invisible Line?" conference, 3/1! 22/80 - position papers II (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Kenyon College, Qambier, Ohio 2/4/80 (John Macionis) (Box 5, Folder 47)
        [corresp 4/79-2/80]
      - Hampshire College 11/10-12/79 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        [Herbert J. Bernstein letter 8/79; Bethany Weidner corresp 3/80]
      - Annenberg School conference 10/17-19/79 (Box 5, Folder 49)
        [corresp w/ George Gerbner, Elvira Lankford 6-10/79]
      - Batavia, Boces Superintendent's Conference Day 10/5/79 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        [Norman C. McLaughlin corresp 8-10/79]
      - "Party Line West Virginia," (public radio) 9/3/79 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Local appearances 1977-79 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Van Deerlin Committee - RKO testimony 6/28/79 (Box 5, Folder 53)
        [text of testimony, press release, RKG: "Public interest is in the mind of the broadcaster, says FCC." In These Times 8/22/79]
      - Van Deerlin Committee testimony - RKG poll 6/79 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Columbus - wedding 8/10-12/ (Box 5, Folder 55)
        [79?]
      - Aspen Institute Seminar, Washington 6/27/79 (Box 5, Folder 56)
        [RKG notes 40pp]
      - Miscellaneous appearances 10/78-6/79 (Box 5, Folder 57)
        [Faculty workshop, Univ. of Lowell, MA 6/8; WOR radio 6/7; Psychology symposium, Alfred Univ 5/17; Wews-TV Cleveland 3/22; "Dilemma '79," Southwestern at Memphis 3/9-11; Fairbanks, Alaska lecture on TV 11/17; Paul Lazarsfeld lecture, Ctr for Rsrch on the Acts of Man, Phila 10/29]
      - Media Ecology conference, Saugerties 4/27-29/79 (Nail Postman) (Box 5, Folder 58)
        [corresp 11/78-4/79; Jim Fowles letter 5/79]
      - FTC hearings on children's advertising 3/30/79 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - University of Manitoba - lecture on television 3/20-22/79 (Box 5, Folder 60)
        [Nicholas Tavuchis corresp 1-2/79; Northwest Orient corresp re difficulties on return flight 4-5/79]
      - "The Television Soap Opera" conference, 8UNY- Buffalo 3/15-16/79 (Box 5, Folder 61)
        [Mary B. Cassata corresp 9/78-3/79]
      - Sage Chapel Convocation: RKG, "Reflections on Myth/ Parable and Human Consciousness," 2/25/79 (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - "A Death in the Family/" Wcco-TV/ Minneapolis 12/3/78 (Box 5, Folder 63)
        [script; letters to Jim Hayden, James M. Rupp letter 11-12/78]
      - "American Women in Radio and Television" conference/ Rochester 10/14/78 (Box 5, Folder 64)
        [letters from Dorothy Cotton, Mrs. Gerry Walker 8-10/78; RKG notes 13pp]
      - American Legal Studies Association conference/ Rutgers 3/16/78 (Ethan Katsch) (Box 5, Folder 65)
        [corresp 11/77-3/78; RKG lecture text: "Public Policy Concerning False and Deceptive TV Commercials" ]
      - Muskingum College convocation/ New Concord/ Ohio 3/1/7 (Box 5, Folder 66)
        [Katherine Schnitker corresp 4/77-3/78]
      - "Ethics of the Midway" - paper delivered at Cornell Symposium/ panel on "Ethics and Public Life" 2/11/78 (Box 5, Folder 67)
        [text llpp]
      - New York State Assembly Committee on Agriculture/ Hearings on Advertising Food to Children - RKG testimony, 11/18/77 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - RKG Statement on American Television and Communication Co. franchise, 6/13/77 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - RKG Lectures, Testimony, TV Program 1973-76 (in reverse chronological order)
      - Aclu Round Table: "Limits to the First Amendment," Cornell University, 2/14/76 - RKG paper (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - "Shaw's View of Women," RKG lecture at Cornell 10/9/75 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        [text, notes]
      - Shaw at Cornell 10/75 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        [RKG notes]
      - Shaw on laughter, good guys/bad guys, humor, artistic vision (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - "Changing Images of Women," lecture at Cornell 1/22/75 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        [review by Judith Bayard in Dialogue: A Newsletter for Cornell Women at Work]
      - RKG testimony on Quello nomination to FCC 1/30/74; "The Practicality of Symbols" 1/30/74; radio program 2/2/74 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - RKG lecture on Polls and Culture Power - transcript: "Philadelphia Communications" (Box 6, Folder 7)
        [c. 1973/4]
      - Surgeon General's Report by the Scientific Advisory Committee on Television and Social Behavior - RKG testimony 3/10/72; letter to Howard Eaton 11/13/71; radio program 9/8/73 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - RKG, "What's Behind the Fig Leaf of TV?" - Act 3, WCIC-TV (Ithaca, NY) 5/29/73) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Show and Tell Machine
    - Elsevier - Scientific Publishing, 1975-76 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovitch, Inc. - Judith Greissman (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Inquiries - Publication Possibilities - Unclassified (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Allan Ravage (Literary Agent) (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Book Prospectus - July 31, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Book Excerpts - 1975, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Dial contract - 1977 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Dial Press correspondence - 1976-79 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Pre-publication comments and correspondence - mostly 7 10/77 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Publicity - general (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Publicity - address labels for prepublication notice (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Publicity - television, radio (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Circulation of bound galleys, selections - 1975-77 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Corrections for public circulating use (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Promotion - inquiries to agencies that arrange lecture: 7-8/77 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - RKG biographical summary prepared for Publicity Department (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - RKG expense receipts - Nov. 1977 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Complimentary copies - 1977 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Complimentary copies - 1978 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Publicity - post-publication (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Fan mail (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Published reviews (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Published reviews - Contemporarv Psychology (Box 6, Folder 59)
      [correspondence w/ John Darley, reviewer]
    - Overseas rights, reviews (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Paperback, reprints and excerpts (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Dell Books - royalty statements, book order (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Book draft (bound): Television: The Product is You (Box 6, Folder 63)
      [c. 1975]
    - The Show And Tell Machine - Book Drafts (previous title - Television: The Product is You)
      - Front material: Title Page, Contents, Foreword (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 1 - "The Television Environment: Stage Set for Desensitization" (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Chapter 1, continued 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 1, continued 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Chapter 2 - "Desensitization and Resensitization: Erosion of Family Feelings" (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Chapter 2, continued (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Chapter 3 - "The Family in Primetime" (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 3, continued (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 4 - "Assembling the Child Market" (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Chapter 5 - "Keep the Child Coming Through the Pipeline (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 6 - "People and Spaces, People in Spaces" (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 7 - "Two Laughs a Minute" (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Chapter 8 - "Cooking Up Audiences" (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Chapter 9 - "Saturating the Sound Environment" (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Chapter 10 - "Forms of Address" (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Chapter 11 - "Words Are a Clumsy Way of Talking" (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Chapter 11, continued (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Chapter 12 - "Involuntary Servitude" (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Chapter 13 - "One Size Fits All: Ratings Stack the Harvest" (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Chapter 14 - "Buying, Selling, and Engineering Software in the Culture Industry" (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Chapter 15 - "Research With and Without Informed Consent" (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Chapter 16 - "Engineering the Appeals to the Child Market" (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Chapter 17 - "Media Research in the Service of Control Not With a Bang, But a Whimper" (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Chapter 18 - "The State is the Good Guy" (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - "Uniforms and Career Apparel" (Box 7, Folder 25)
        [subject matter similar Chapter 18]
      - Chapter 19 - "Literacy Without Books: Sesame Street" (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Chapter 20 - "The Marketing of Auras" (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - "The Mickey Mouse Club: Initiation Into Consumerhood" (Box 7, Folder 28)
        [subject matter similar to Chapter 20]
      - Chapter 21 - "Command/ Obey. Thought/Imagination. Ford/Disney." (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Footnotes - Jan. 13, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Index, Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Series III.Correspondence
  - Alphabetical
    - A (Box 8, Folder 1)
      [2 to Donna Alien (Women's Institute for Freedom of the Press) 10-12/80; 2 from Robert Ascher 2/73]
    - Adair Films (Janet Cole) 8-9/79 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      [lit. on Word Is Out]
    - Robert Alley and Irby Brown 9-10/82 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Michael Arlen ll/ [77?] -9/82 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Robert Amove 6/78-1/84 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      [Amove, "A View from Nicaragu Literacy Campaigns and the Transformation of Political Culture" 11/82]
    - Jaime Arocha 8/73-8/80 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      [in English, Spanish; articles]
    - Sylvia Ashton-Warner - nomination for A.D. White Professor-at-Large 3/73-8/74 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      [correspondence w/ several Cornell faculty, etc.]
    - Aspen Institute 10/78-1/80 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      [memos, questionnaires]
    - B (Box 8, Folder 9)
      [Amy Rebecca Bach - c.v.; Richard Barnet 1-12/74, review of Global Reach by Barnet and Ronald Muller 4/7 Rena Bartos 6-7/80, clipping; Robert Beggs 3/78; Sandy Bern 6-7/79; Michel Benamou - news of death 9/80; Alice Gail Bier 6/83; Ingrid Rose Blomgren 1/83; Thorbjorn Broddason 5-7/79; William L. Brown - c.v.; Susan Brownmiller (Women Against Pornography) 9/79; Jennifer W. Brice 1978; Bruzzone Research Company 8/78]
    - Gregory Bateson 2-3/64, 10/72-4/73 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      ["Cybernetic Explanation" from Steps to an Ecology of Mind; "Greqory Bateson: Understanding Whole Systems" 12/74; "A Conversation with Gregory Bateson" by John Welwood; RE notes]
    - Gregory Bateson's visit to Cornell 4/15/75 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      [letters, memos, publicity, RKG notes, clipping]
    - Azriel Bibliowicz 5/79-3/84 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Drie Bronfenbrenner 7/73-8/74 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      ["Experimental Human Ecology" 1974; Foundation for Child Development funding guidelines 1974]
    - Stuart N. Brotman 9-10/80 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      ["Redesigning Television"; review of The View from Sunset Boulevard by Ben Stein 1979]
    - C (Box 8, Folder 15)
      [Caravan Surveys (Harry O'Neill) 6/79 - not sent; Amy Carlin - internship c. 1981; Center for Communications (Frank Stanton), w/ clipping 7/80; Peggy Charen (Action for Children's Television) 7/80; Charlotte Cohen -recommendation 4/80; Cornell University Press (Barbara Burnham) 2/80; Alice Cook 2-3/80; June Cross 10/80]
    - Edmund Carpenter 1/73-9/82 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      [RKG notes re Carpenter's visit to Cornell 2/74]
    - Mary Cassata (SUNY-Buffalo) 1/78-4/79 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      [research plan]
    - Geoffrey Chester - salary negotiations 12/80-3/81 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Coalition for Public Rights in Broadcasting 1978 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      [National Citizens Communications Lobby literature]
    - Dorothy and Louis Cohen 3/75-12/79 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      ["Is TV a Pied Piper?" 3/74]
    - Communication control Systems (Marvin Olarsch) c.1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      [ads; RKG notes; no letters]
    - Alice Cook 8/70-7/72, 2-3/80 (Box 8, Folder 21A)
    - D-E (Box 8, Folder 22)
      [Jesus M. Delgado - business card; Ken Donow 6/80, c.v.; Murray Edelman 8-9/75; Loren Eiseley 2/73; Enterprise Square (John R. March) 7/79; Joseph R. Eraza 2/79, project proposal]
    - Patrick Esmonde-White 10-11/82 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      [learning agreement w/ Union Grad School; RKG recommendation]
    - P (Box 8, Folder 24)
      [Adele M. Fasick 5-6/80; Federal Communications Commission 8/78; Federal Trade Commission (William P. Golden) 7/78; Richard B. Fischer 2/80; Michael A. Forscey 7/80, William F. Whyte to Forscey 3/80; Howard H. Frederick 9/82; Bernard Z. Friedlander (NSF Child Research Project) 6-10/76]
    - Valerie Faith 9/78-5/79 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      [c.v.; Faith and Linda Shaw Finlay, "'Illiteracy and Alienation': Studying the Philosophy of Paulo Freire with American College Students" 6/78]
    - Jan and Cornelia Flora 9/73-2/81 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      [Cornelia Flora, "The Fotonovela in Latin America" c. 1980; Jan Flora, Agricultura: Sector Lider de la Revolucion Cubana" c. 1980]
    - Roger B. Fransecky and Associates, Inc. 10/78 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      ["Hanging Out" newsletters 9/78]
    - Ellen Franklin 1/74-8/79 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - G (Box 8, Folder 29)
      [Margaret Gallagher 9/78-2/79; Nicholas Garnham 7-10/80, "Politics and the Mass Media in Britain" 1979; R.B. Grant 12/82; Jeff Greenfield 3/79]
    - Willard Gaylin and others at Hastings Institute 3/72-11/77 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      [Gaylin 3-4/72, 11/77; Robert Neville 5-12/72; Bruce Hilton 12/72]
    - George Gerbner (Annenberg School of Communications) 6/71-7/79 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Regina Gibaja 12/71-4/83 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      [English and Spanish]
    - Joseph M. Goldsen 8-9/71, 8/78 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      ["The Impact of New Mod of Transmission" 4/71, c.v.]
    - H (Box 8, Folder 34)
      [Mike Haller 7-8/81; Sharen Hansen 10/78; Dan Haverkamp 2-8/79; Hoso-Bunka Foundation 8/80; Herbert Hyman 1/83, RKG, Bureau of Applied Social Research 20t Anniversary Address 4/27/57]
    - Shirley Harkness 2/7 4-6/7 8 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Donald Hayes - Sociology Department 8-12/80 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      [re salary negotiations, etc.; professional profiles of RKG and 4 other Soc. Dept. faculty; RKG notes]
    - John Hess 9/74-7/80 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Holly Hope 9/80 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      ["Cross-cultural and 'Trans-historical Perspectives in Social Theory: C. Wright Mills and Jvirgen Habermas" 10/79]
    - Barbara Howe 11/73-5/81 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      [c.v.; "Biographical Statement on Research Directions" 9/80; "Book Proposal" 1981; "Description of Proposed Course" 1981; RKG recommendations ]
    - I-J (Box 8, Folder 40)
      [International Institute of Communications Ltd. 3/77; James Jacobs - RKG to Don Hayes 1/78]
    - Institute for Policy Studies 9/73-12/80 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      [Marcus Raskin et al]
    - Image-nation (David Lent) 2/78-3/79 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Journal of Social Reconstruction 8/78-7/80 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      [prospectus project proposals; Marcus Raskin letters; Bethany Weidner, "Toward a Definition of Reconstructive Knowledge"]
    - K (Box 8, Folder 44)
      [Ethan Katsch 12/79-2/83, c.v., RKG recommendation; Flora Klein-Andreu 9/82, "Account of Career," "Direct and Indirect Effects of Population Changes on Language Norms in Spain"; Jerzy Kosinsky 3/79; H.E. Krugman (General Electric) 11/78; Norton L. Kurland 12/82-3/83 Susan M. Kurz]
    - Harold Kohn (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - L (Box 8, Folder 46)
      [Suzanne K. Langer 2/76, RKG notes; Louis Lemkow 6/8 c.v.; Arthur Lipow 3/73; Longhouse - party invitation 6/79; Marshall Lumsden 3-4/79]
    - Joshua Lederberg 1966, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      ["Experimental Genetics am Human Evolution" 10/66 w/ RKG summary; "Biological Innovation and Genetic Intervention" 1972; "Egg Transplants: Not the End of the World" 1971]
    - Adeline Levine 3/79-10/83 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      ["The Idea of the Coffee Pot Lessons Learned from a Systems Innovation" 1977; A.L. and Murray Levine, "The Social Context of Evaluative Research" 11/77; "Who Does What to Whom? The Media and Science at Love Canal" 9/83]
    - Adeline Levine - visiting lecture 3/15/83 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      [correspondence, publicity, text of talk]
    - M [A. Kent McDougall 2-4/80; Robin MacNeil; Frank Mankiewicz 9/79; Marisa Manley 1/79-2/80; Robert Karl Manoff 4/81; Frank Mauro 11/79; Jean McPheeters c.v.; Jesus M. de Miguel 6-11/83; Sid Mintz 4/79; Kathryn Currier Moody 12/77-9/80, reviews of Moody, Growing Up On Television 1980; Bill Movers 5/791 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Jerry Mander 11/77-6/79 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Lynne and Grant Masland 9/74-1/76 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      [English and Spanish G.M., "When the Masses Control the Media" 2/71; L.M. ai G.M., "Some Cross-Cultural Implications of Educational TV: The Samoan ETV Project" 6/72]
    - MIT Press - Evaluation of Donis Dondi's book [Television Literacy"] 4-5/80 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Jose A. Moreno 9/77-1/79 (Box 8, Folder 54)
      [c.v.'s; RKG recommendation]
    - N (Box 8, Folder 55)
      [National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting 6/79-7/81; Dorothy Nelkin 7-8/71, 11-12/80; Northwest Orient Airlines 3/79]